you wouldn't even be talking about you know
immigration first you wouldn't even be talking
this is not a subject that was on anybody's
mind until like running up my announcement
and i used to
mexico is and except the reporters because
they're very dishonest life generally speaking
in the world the politics they didn't cover
my statement the way i said
the fact is
since then many killings murders crime drugs
for you across the border are money going
out and the drugs coming in and i said we
need to build a wall
and it has to be built quickly and i don't
mind having a big beautiful door in the wall
so that people can come into this country
legally
what we need to see that they're filled a
wall we need to keep
he goes out
this is a little bit in thirty seconds
i'll give you thirty seconds to answer my
question which was watching evidence do you
have a specific evidence
but the mexican government is everything
at all across the border thirty like a border
patrol i was at double murder last week
border patrol people that i deal with that
i talk too they say this is what's happening
because our leaders a stupid are politicians
are stupid
and the mexican government is much smarter
much you are much more coming and they send
the bad ones over because they don't want
to pay for
they don't want to take care of them why
i should say when this stupid leaders of
the united states will do what forms and
that's what's happening with do you like
it or not
all right
obviously there's a lot more to talk about
this we're going to have more questions for
the candidates on illegal immigration but
other key topics including your questions
on facebook
were you were doing is making immigration
easier to those want to do it legally what
specific steps would you see
you can see the two places like to know what
the candidates even if you can see some changes
in my own country again
welcome back to fox news facebook republican
debate tonight we're going to continue the
questions now on illegal immigration we kind
of ended with a cliffhanger there so let's
continue the conversation in a case like
i know you don't like to talk about donald
trump
but i do want to ask you about the merits
of what he just said
when you say that it on the american government
is too but that the mexican government is
sending criminals a that were being banned
both is not an adequate response
the question of all the illegal in the right
wrist personally was just saying to chris
christie they say we're outspoken we typically
take the track record that we're really going
to learn that there's something about donald
trump
donald trump to the in this country
you see the number of people are frustrated
they're fair at all
they don't think the government is working
for him and for people don't want to just
two them out there making a mistake
now he's got his solutions some of us have
other solutions you know we've got to balance
the federal budget is one of the chief architect
when i was in washington hasn't been done
since
i was a military performer former high took
of the state of ohio from an eight billion
dollar hole in the three hundred fifty thousand
job loss
to a two billion dollar surplus and again
you know three hundred fifty thousand jobs
respect speculation we talk about all i want
it but the point is that we all have solutions
mister trump
is touching a nerve because people want the
world to be built they want to see an end
to illegal immigration they as we all do
we all have different ways of getting there
you're going to hear from all of us tonight
about what our ideas are all right well you
know senator rubio let me back and do better
what you know
it is it is simple as our leaders are stupid
and their leaders are smart and all of these
illegals coming over are criminals but let
me set the record straight on a couple things
the first the evidence is now clear that
the majority of people coming across the
border or not from mexico they're coming
from guatemala el salvador honduras
those countries of the for the source of
the people that are now coming in the majority
i also believe we need a friend
the problem is a real trouble bill the tunnel
under the fence we have to be able to deal
with that too and that's why you need any
verify system you need an intrinsic tracking
system and all sorts of other things to prevent
illegal immigration
but i really remember casey governor kasich
is and people are frustrated this is the
most generous country in the world when it
comes to immigration there are a million
people a year legally immigrate to the united
states and people feel like we're being taken
advantage of
we feel like despite our generosity we are
being taken advantage of and let me tell
you will never get to talk about in these
debates the people to call my office
we've been waiting for fifteen years to come
to the united states and they pay their for
you and they hired a lawyer and they can't
get in and they're wondering maybe they should
come illegally
and so these are important issues and we
should address that it's a serious problem
that needs to be
and otherwise we're going to keep talking
about this for the next thirty years like
we have for the last thirty years film under
water
in the water from the two thousand two to
as recently as twenty thirteen just two years
ago you supported comprehensive immigration
reform including a path to citizenship know
you say that was a quick reaction to something
i really thought about
and that you change your mind
other than politics could you explain why
in the last two years you change your position
on the path to citizenship i know there are
other kinds of positions that we shouldn't
hold to
yeah well kristie actually sit on your show
earlier this year if i don't know that now
is that i said actually listen to the american
people and i think people across america
one a leader who's actually get to listen
to them i talked a border state governors
and other elected officials i look at how
this president vertically through last november
messed up the immigration system this country
most important i listen to the people
over i believe we need to secure the border
i've been to the border with governor happen
in texas and others seeing the problems they
have there there's international criminal
organisations penetrating are certain base
borders we need to do something about it
secure the border enforce the law no amnesty
and go for the legal immigration system to
give priority to american working families
and wages
and it's really some fourteen hundred people
submitted questions on this very not talk
about the illegal immigration is on facebook
and the number of them were about the murder
of the time in san francisco allegedly shot
down by an elite
don knapp reports and this question will
you support case finally for with impose
imposing mandatory five year prison term
for the illegal who supported and then returned
to this country and will you define the same
story city is for violating federal
chris absolutely yes
and not only one life support it
i have four thirty case law and the united
states senate in file that legislation
i tried to get the senate to vote to pass
case law on the floor the senate just one
week ago and the leader of our own party
blocked a vote on case law
you know
there was reference made to our leaders being
stupid it's not a question of stupidity
it's they don't want to enforce the immigration
law
but there are far too many in the washington
cartel that supported the president promised
talked about fundamentally transporting this
country
there's seven million people across the face
of the of many of the want to come to this
country they come illegally great but if
they come here illegally
and they get and the that is how we fundamentally
change this country and it really is striking
a majority of the candidates on the stage
of supported amnesty i have never supported
and the state and i led the fight against
chuck schumer gang of eight in the state
legislation and stuff
i don't going to switch topics out and talk
a bit about air and national security
and
you said that senator paul opposition to
the an collection of phone records has made
the united states weaker and more vulnerable
even going so far as to say that he should
be called before congress to answer for it
if we should be hit by another terrorist
attack
you really believe you can assign blame the
center apologist for opposing
the bulk collection of people's phone records
in the event of a terrorist attack
yes i do
i'll tell you why because i'm the only person
to see who's actually filed applications
to the patriot act who have gone before the
federal the foreign intelligence service
corps i prosecuted and investigated in jail
terrorists in this country after september
eleven th
i was deployed u. s. attorney by president
bush on september ten th two thousand one
and the world changed enormously the next
day and happen in my state this is not theoretical
to me i went to the we lost friends of ours
in trade center that day my own wife was
two blocks from the trade centre that their
office and gone through that morning
when you actually have to be responsible
for doing this you can do it and we did it
for seven years in my office respecting civil
liberties and protecting the homeland and
i will make no apologies ever for protecting
the lives and the safety of the american
people we have to give more tools
to our phones to be able to do that not work
and then trust those people in overseas them
to do with the right way as president spent
exactly what else do they get married
yeah
i want to collect more records from terrorist
less records from innocent americans
for him and then we've got a revolution over
john adams said it was the spark that much
or war for independence
and i'm proud of standing for the bill of
rights and i will continue to stand for the
bill of rights and
very effective
you know that's a completely ridiculous answer
i want to collect more records from terrorists
let's records for older people how are you
supposed to know you support him how are
you so beautiful no matter how you but i
don't know because of the you know it's there
you that make
going to make it like this and answer you
know when you're sitting in the sub committee
just blowing hot air about this
you can see things like that when you're
responsible for protecting the lives of the
american people
i mean what she two men many is to make sure
that you know the way to the were probably
governor you fundamentally un misunderstand
the bill of rights
every time you do the case you got any more
it from a job i'm talking about searches
without warrant to read indiscriminately
all americans records and that's what i thought
and i don't trust because you know bomb or
records i know you guys him a big if you
want to give them a big over again so i
yeah
i know
you know sort of law
well you know the hopes that i remember or
the that i do the families who lost their
people on september eleven th hotel i remember
i know you know for the to i know
nothing to do with politics on like what
you're doing like cutting speeches on the
floor of the senate the podium on the internet
within a half an hour to raise money for
your campaign right and while still putting
our country ratsiraka i know exactly where
they want to get there
i is going to be that kind of think because
they have a negative to get i really want
to get to face a questionnaire a and without
shelter and she has a following
yeah
how kind of is actually
and strong in influence in the u. s. they
were you concerned
they're crazy want to talk to you about this
because many of the facebook users and then
the folks on but one of the ice of tonight
us the chair of the joint chiefs
a question what would it take to destroy
exist in ninety days he tell you i can only
be totally destroyed once they rejected by
the population in which they live and then
you accuse him of pushing medicaid for the
iraqis
how would you just write i said in ninety
days
making a away nato commander and cheese
it speaks the truth
we will not just see radical islamic terrorists
so long as we had the president unwilling
to utter the words radical islamic terrorists
and general dempsey the chairman of the joint
chiefs what would be required militarily
to destroy i as he said there is no military
solution we need to change the conditions
on the ground so that young men or not in
poverty and susceptible to radical as they
should that with all due respect is nonsense
it's the same it to the state department
gave that we need to give them jobs what
we needed that commander in chief who makes
clear if you join ices
you wage jihad on america
then you were signing your desk or you don't
say i am lot
i have
and i don't know the area
i think it of course it's an ideological
problem that's one of the reasons why i introduced
the expatriate terrorist act in the senate
that said if any american travels to the
middle east and us is that he or she forfeits
their citizenship so they don't use the past
for come back in the way
on america
yes it is ideological and conference president
obamas about the prayer breakfast
it's actually acted as an apologist
he said well gosh the crusade inquisition
we need a president that shows the courage
the egypt's president elsisi did most of
when he called out the radical islamic terrorists
are threatening the door
hey and this campaign he struggled to answer
a question about whether knowing what we
know now i remember in beirut america
i remember too
and i said of course is now thriving there
you finally