life which is most vulnerable and the newborn
child a son as general hospital receives
the care he needs and is
but that has not always been the case here
where in the past the lives of babies and
mothers have needlessly being put at risk
midwives who would known as the most good
she is working in the unit that was dysfunctional
resisted what they saw as interference from
doctors
obviously all heartbroken call hendrickson
and his wife and islam as a heart stopped
in the maternity unit following the fit fire
was a i'm of my life
and so much
you know on a best friend
so that
we don't cope with without very well i don't
think more
without loss in the way she died
so a factor
you know it's hard pressed to flee hard for
the following day calls newborn son chester
olson died
after several years of incompetence dishonesty
in cover up but the hospital says there is
the full extent of its lethal mix of deficiencies
is finally being laid back
today is human
to cut world is unforgivable and to file
the is inexcusable
these woods was spoken just over ten years
ago by a great jump in the patient safety
and chief medical officer for the and almost
those of you have seen every poll will know
that could have been spoken with smoking
by in mind
why sarah brown is general hospital with
that to be in denial pursuing any cost what
they regarded as normal but
but what makes this latest investigation
all the more shocking is that it unveils
the wife individual families who when they
tried to take on the all far to one not give
them the protection and support from the
very and they cast watchdogs was that help
to protect patients
in cumbria families of those who lost babies
at the hospital watch together as the health
secretary gave his response speaking of the
trauma that had ceased
nothing we say we do today can take away
that i
so we can at least provide beyonces to the
families questions about what happened and
why and in doing so trying to prevent a similar
tragedy in the future
for the very you it's just being the long
and sometimes but to fight against the mighty
many influential individuals and several
official bodies
i don't think will be entirely satisfied
that and everything every time i think it
is how does that a safety feeling that everyone
in the in an attack
investigations into individual midwives amount
to just continue well many families who should
have had members of one of the best days
of the lawyers going grieving the loss of
mothers and babies who could have survived